Starting a new job, moving house, quitting your job to start a new business – all of these can be great opportunities, but all of them can lead to uncertainty.
开始新工作、搬家、辞职创业——这些都是很好的机会，但它们都可能带来不确定性。
We can't know for sure that they will turn out well.
我们无法确定它们会发展得很好。
Could this fear of the unknown be holding us back?
这种对未知的恐惧会不会阻碍我们前进呢？
Improving things in your life often requires some uncertainty, whether that's making time to learn something new, or moving to a new area.
改善生活中的事情往往需要一些不确定性，无论是挤出时间学习新东西，还是搬到新的地区。
And it's not just about radical change.
这不仅仅关乎彻底的改变。
We often make negative assumptions about people we don't know, but if we go through the uncertainty of getting to know someone new, we can establish positive social or working relationships.
我们常常对不认识的人做出消极的假设，但如果我们经历过了解新人的不确定性，就可以建立积极的社交或工作关系。
So, how can we learn to make the most of uncertainty?
那么，我们如何学会充分利用不确定性呢？
First, it can help to adjust the way we think about not knowing what will happen.
首先，调整我们对未知结果的思考方式会有所帮助。
Being curious about a new job can help us grow, while being afraid of any negative changes can stop us taking advantage of new opportunities.
对新工作保持好奇可以帮助我们成长，而对任何负面变化的恐惧则会阻止我们利用新的机会。
It can be helpful to see threats as challenges that can be overcome.
将威胁视为可以克服的挑战对我们大有益处。
One thing that can help with this is having faith in your own abilities.
有件事可以对此有帮助，就是相信自己的能力。
When assessing an uncertain future situation, consider your own capability in being able to mitigate any issues that come up.
在评估不确定的未来情况时，要考虑自己是否有能力应对出现的任何问题。
If you know that you have the skills, knowledge or flexibility required to address unforeseen problems, then uncertainty can seem like less of a threat.
如果你知道自己拥有解决不可预见问题所需的技能、知识或灵活性，那么不确定性似乎就不那么具有威胁了。
Believing in yourself is one way to build resilience.
相信自己是一种建立适应力的方式。
E-commerce entrepreneur Alexandre Bonvin highlights the importance of building up a cash buffer in business.
电子商务企业家亚历山大·邦万强调了在企业中建立现金缓冲的重要性。
Another way to build your resilience can be to take on small tasks that have some uncertainty and reflecting on how you deal with each one.
另一种建立韧性的方法是承担一些具有不确定性的小任务，并反思你如何应对每一个任务。
A positive mindset and building up our own personal resilience can help us use uncertainty as an opportunity for growth.
积极的心态和建立我们自己的韧性可以帮助我们将不确定性作为成长的机会。